Guide to the Elmer Eric E. E. Schattschneider Papers, 1901 - 1971 (bulk 1955-1971)
Elmer Eric "E. E." Schattschneider Papers, 1901 - 1971 (bulk 1955-1971)
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Schattschneider, E. E. (Elmer Eric), 1892-1971.
1000-9
13
14
Schattschneider was the author of numerous books and articles about American government and American political parties. Schattschneider was president of the American Political Science Association (1956-57), and spent the majority of his career (1930-71) teaching at Wesleyan University.
The E. E. Schattschneider Papers include correspondence, speeches and writings, student projects from Schattschneider's seminars on performing local community surveys, subject files of background material and notes for individual books as well as general subject files, family photographs, a documentary film written and presented by Schattschneider, and a collection of books annotated by Schattschneider.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions
Acquisitions Information
Acquired by Clement E. Vose following Schattschneider's death and kept by Vose as an unprocessed collection within the Collection on Legal Change.
Biographical Note
Chronology List
1892 Born, Bethany MN, August 11.
1915 A.B., University of Wisconsin. Phi Beta Kappa.
1916 Works for the YMCA for two years.
1918 Serves in the Navy for one year.
1919 Teaches at Senior High School, Butler PA, until 1926.
1926 Wallace Fellow in Political Science, University of Pittsburgh.
1927 M.A., University of Pittsburgh.
1927-1930 Instructor in Government, Columbia University.
1929-1930 Assistant Professor of Political Science, New Jersey College for Women (now Rutgers University)
1930-1935 Assistant Professor of Government, Wesleyan University
1935 Ph.D., Columbia University.
1935-1939 Associate Professor of Government, Wesleyan University.
1938-1940 Member, City Council, Middletown CT.
1939-1960 John E. Andrus Professor of Government, Wesleyan University.
1940-1946 Member, [Connecticut] State Board of Mediation and Arbitration.
1944-1952 Member, Board of Directors, The Rockfall Corporation, Middletown CT.
1946-1951 Consultant Editor, Rinehart & Co.
August 1949 Travels to Germany as a visiting expert for the U.S. Army of Occupation.
1949-1950 Visiting professor at Syracuse University supervising the studies of 20 visiting German students.
1949 Chair, Committee on Political Parties, American Political Science Association. Report of the committee was published in 1950 as Toward a More Responsible Two-Party System.
1950-1955 Member, Board of Directors, Long Lane School, Middletown CT. President of Board, 1953-1955.
1951 Chair, Governor's Commission of Community Adjustment Problems.
1953-1954 Vice-president, American Political Science Association.
1955-1961 Chair, Public Affairs Center, Wesleyan University.
1955 Receives Moravian College Annual Alumni Award.
1956-1957 President, American Political Science Association.
1956-1962 Member, Board of Trustees, National Center for Education in Politics.
1957-1961 Chairman, Board of Directors, Citizenship Clearing House, an organization that encourages college students to enter politics.
1958 Receives Freedom Foundation award for Democracy as a Moral System, a television discussion with Julian Hartt of Yale University.
1960-1971 Professor Emeritus of Government, Wesleyan University. Taught courses at Wesleyan through 1970.
1960 Receives L.L.D. degree [honorary], Moravian College.
1967-1968 Member, Charter Study Commission, Old Saybrook, CT.
1969 Receives James L. McConaughy Memorial Award, Wesleyan Alumni Council.
March 4, 1971 Dies.
Collection Overview
This collection contains the papers of E. E. Schattschneider, a political scientist who spent the majority of his career at Wesleyan University. This collection is organized into seven series and primarily reflects Schattschneider's research interests from the 1950s until his death in 1971. All series are arranged alphabetically by name or subject and chronologically thereunder, with the exception of Series 3, Teaching, Wesleyan Government Department, Student Papers, each section of which is arranged chronologically, and alphabetically thereunder. Schattschneider's original order and nomenclature for folder titles have been retained throughout wherever possible; renaming and further description is present where the original titles have been nonexistant or extremely misleading.
Series 1, Correspondence, includes primarily incoming correspondence concerning professional activities, teaching, speeches and publications. Other notable groups include correspondence with Schattschneider's publishers concerning several of his books, organizational correspondence relating to Schattschneider's NBC television series American Government and the Pursuit of Happiness (1957), and correspondence concerning visiting professorships at American universities. Correspondents include many elected officials from Connecticut from the 1940s-60s including Chester Bowles, John Dempsey, and Abraham Ribicoff. Other correspondents include Harold H. Burton, J. William Fulbright, Samuel P. Huntington, Estes Kefauver, Henry Cabot Lodge, Adlai Stevenson, and Arthur T. Vanderbilt. Cross-references have been noted for persons appearing in more than one location if their corporate or university affiliation changes. Correspondence notation lists the amount of incoming correspondence first, followed by outgoing correspondence (e.g. Brown, Joseph R. 3/0, 1967-68).
Series 2, Writings and Speeches, contains notes, drafts, corrected typescripts, and author proofs for several of Schattschneider's books including Party Government, A Guide to the Study of Public Affairs, The Semi-Sovereign People, and Two Hundred Million Americans in Search of a Government. This series also contains documents, including corrected typescripts, for an unpublished volume or volumes titled, at various times, The Great American Experiment and The Resolution of Conflict - An Explanation of American Government, the latter of which Schattschneider was completing at the time of his death, and typescripts of several unpublished speeches and lectures.
Included in other series are student projects from Schattschneider's seminars on performing local community surveys, subject files of background material and notes for individual books as well as general subject files, family photographs, a documentary film written and presented by Schattschneider, and a collection of books annotated by Schattschneider.
Collection Arrangement
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Faculty.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.). Government Dept.; Schattschneider, E. E. (Elmer Eric), 1892-1971.; United States --Politics and government --20th century.; Local government --United States.; Political science --Study and teaching.; Political parties --United States.; American Political Science Association.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Series 1. Correspondence
  - A-Am (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Abbey, Robert, 1948
    - Adams, Sherman, 1957
    - Addison, Herbert J., 1970
    - Adrian, Charles R., 1953
    - Alexander, Herbert E., 1953
    - Altschuler, Jonathan B., 1967
    - Encyclopedia Americana Annual, 1949-1952
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1968
    - American Education Press, 1951
    - American Institute of Public Opinion, 1948
    - American Jewish Committee, 1954
  - American Political Science Association, 1944-1961
  - Am-Ay
    - American Political Science Review, 1944-1952
    - American Society for Public Administration, 1949
    - American University, 1940-1953
    - American Veteran's Committee, Columbia U. Chapter, 1948
    - American Veteran's Committee, Harvard U. Chapter, 1948
    - The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1948-1954
    - Appleby, Paul H., 1947-1954
    - Archon Books, 1966
    - Arnold, Jeff, 1967
    - Audience Surveys, Inc., 1948
    - Automobile Mutual Insurance Co. of America, 1953
    - N.W. Ayer & Son, Inc., 1951
  - B-Ba (Folder 4)
    - Babu, V. Vithal, 1952
    - Bahm, Archie J., 1954
    - Baier, Clarence W., 1954
    - Bailey, Stephen K., 1948-1969
    - Baldwin, Raymond E., 1948-1950
    - Baldwin, Robert H., 1952
    - Baldwin, Sidney, 1951-1952
    - Ball, M. Margaret, 1948-1952
    - Baptist Student Foundation, 1954
    - Bard, Erwin W., 1954
    - Barron's Educational Series, Inc., 1970-1971
    - Bateman, Raymond H., 1954
    - Baxter, Caleb G., 1951
  - Be-Bo
    - Beck, James H., 1951
    - Bellush, Jewel, 1948
    - Bennet, Douglas J., Sr., 1949-1950
    - Bennington College, 1953
    - Benton, William, 1952
    - Berdahl, Clarence A., 1953
    - Beszal, Egon E., 1953
    - Binkley, Wilfred E., 1951
    - Bishop, Donald G., 1950-1952
    - Bloch, Heinz, 1953
    - Blodgett, Grace M., 1953
    - Bok, Nellie Lee, 1954
    - Bone, Hugh A., 1952-1953
    - The Cyrenius H. Booth Library, 1953
    - Boston University, 1949-1953
    - Borger, Henry C., Jr., 1953
    - Bowles, Chester, 1949-1952
  - Br-Bu
    - Brandeis University, 1949
    - Bricker, John W., 1930-1934
    - Bridgewater Connecticut Democratic Town Committee, 1950
    - Brodigan, George D., 1953
    - Brown, Joseph R., 1967-1968
    - Brown, MacAlister, 1953
    - Brown, Richard C., 1953
    - Bruce, Harold R., 1949
    - Bureau of Governmental Research, 1951
    - Burns, James M., 1948-1954
    - Burton, Harold H., 1957
    - Butterfield, Victor, 1948-1963
  - C-Ch
    - California Institute of Technology, 1952
    - Carlson, Stephen, 1968
    - Carr, Robert K., 1953
    - Case, Clifford P., 1950
    - Cavan, Ruth S., 1954
    - Celler, Emanuel, 1950
    - Chamberlain, Lawrence H., 1948-1953
    - Charlesworth, James C., 1953
    - Cherington, Charles R., 1954
    - University of Chicago, Committee on Social Thought, 1950
    - University of Chicago Press, 1954-1960
    - University of Chicago, Public Affairs Conference Center, 1961-1962
    - Chiedk, Harwood L., 1949
    - Christian Action, 1952-1953
    - The Christian Democratic World Society, 1951
  - Ci (Folder 8)
    - The Citizenship Clearing Houses, 1948-1960
    - Citizenship Educational Project, Columbia University, 1949-1955
  - Cl-Con (Folder 9)
    - Clark, Robert A., 1952
    - Colegrove, Kenneth, 1948
    - College of the Holy Cross, 1953
    - Collins, Morris W. H., 1954
    - Columbia University, Teachers College, 1951-1954
    - Committee for Economic Development, 1945
    - Committee on Friendly Relations Among Foreign Students, 1951
    - Community Club of South Glastonbury, 1951
    - Conaway, O. B. Jr., 1953
    - Congress of Industrial Organization, 1953
    - Congressional Quarterly, 1951
    - Connecticut College, 1951-1954
    - Connecticut Council of Churches, 1948
    - Connecticut State Industrial Union Council, 1948
    - Connecticut State Labor Council, AFL-CIO, 1965
  - Connecticut, State of, 1937-1969 (Folder 10)
  - Con-Cr (Folder 11)
    - Connecticut, University of, 1947-1953
    - Cook, Virginia G., 1953
    - Copystat Co., 1945
    - Cornell University, 1953
    - Council Against Communist Aggression, 1951
    - Council for Social Action, 1951-1953
    - Crippen, David R., 1953
  - D-De (Folder 12)
    - Dahl, Robert A., 1949
    - The Dallas Morning News, 1945
    - Davenport, Frederick M., 1952
    - David, Paul T., 1954
    - Davie, Harold W., 1950
    - Davis, Harry R., 1953
    - Davis, Jerome, 1951
    - Davison, George W., 1951-1952
    - Dembert, Don Frank, 1954
    - The Democratic National Committee, 1952-1969
    - Dewing, Mrs. Leonard, undated
    - Dexter, Lewis A., 1965
  - Di-Dy (Folder 13)
    - Dibble, Carl, 1951
    - Donovan, John C., 1953
    - Downes, Joseph B., 1954
    - The Dryden Press Inc., 1952-1953
    - Duncombe, David C., 1954
    - DuPont Co., 1952
    - Dyke, Peter, 1950
  - E
    - Eibenstein, 1951
    - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1952
    - Emory University, 1953-1954
    - Encyclopaedia Britannica Films, Inc., 1951
    - Englebert, Ernest A., 1948
    - Engler, Robert, 1949-1951
    - Eriangen, Heinrich V., 1953
    - Etherington, Edwin D., 1967
    - Exchange Club of Hartford, 1952
  - F-Fe (Folder 15)
    - Fainsod, Merle, 1948
    - Falk, Eugene H., 1952
    - The Maurice and Laura Falk Foundation, 1952-1962
    - Farrar & Rinehart, Inc., 1940-1945
    - Fenno, Richard, 1953
    - Ferguson, LeRoy, 1952
    - Fessler, James W., 1954
  - Fi-Fu (Folder 16)
    - Field, G. Lowell, 1950-1953
    - Filley, Walter O., Jr., 1951-1960
    - Fleming, John G., 1953
    - Fletcher, John L., Jr., 1953-1954
    - B. C. Forbes & Sons Publishing Co., Inc., 1953
    - Fretwell, Elbert K., Jr., 1953-1954
    - Frost, Richard, undated
    - Fuchs, Larry, 1953
    - Fulbright, J. William, 1950-1957
  - G-Gr
    - Galloway, George B., 1955
      See also: United States Senate, Committee on Expenditure in the Executive Department.
    - Gamma Phi Club of Delta Kappa Epsilon, 1950
    - Garfinkel, Herbert, 1953
    - Gaus, John M., 1948-1949
    - General Electric Co., 1964
    - George, John J., 1952
    - Gill, Thomas D., 1945
    - Goldbloom, A. Allen, 1953
    - Goodwin, George, Jr., 1953
    - Gossett, Ed, 1950-1951
    - Governmental Affairs Institute, 1952
    - Grady, Gerald J., 1953
    - Grattan, William J., 1953
    - Gregg, A. Phyllis, 1952
    - Grossman, Walter, 1951
  - Ha (Folder 18)
    - Hall, Chadwick, 1952
    - Hallstein, Walter, 1953
    - Hancher, Virgil M., 1953
    - Hancock, John S., 1969
    - Hancock, Stewart F., 1954
    - Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1950
    - Hardin, Charles M., 1969
    - Harkness, J. Marion, 1951
    - Harris, Joseph P., 1952
    - Harris, Robert J., 1948, 1953
    - Hartford Times, 1950-1951
    - Hartt, Julian, 1957 Enc.
    - Harvard University, 1948-1952
    - Harvard Law Review, 1949
    - Hatt, John H., 1951
    - Haverford College, undated
    - Hawkins, Lester G., 1948-1953
    - Hawley Manor, 1953 Enc.
    - Hawley, William W., 1953
  - He-Ho (Folder 19)
    - Heady, Ferrel, 1949
    - Heard, Alexander, 1950
    - Hearst Promotion Enterprises, 1951
    - Hechler, Kenneth W., 1953
    - Heffiou, Paul T., 1953
    - Herzberg, Donald, 1947-1953
    - Hill, G. Albert, 1951
    - Hill, Perry C., 1948
    - Hiscock, William McC., 1952
    - Hobart and William Smith Colleges, 1953, 1967
    - Holcombe, Arthur N., 1937
    - Holcombe, Harold G., 1949
    - Hoefling, Heribert, circa 1950s
    - Hollins College, undated
    - Henry Holt and Company, Inc., 1951-1960
  - Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc., 1951, 1961-1971 Enc. (Folder 20)
    Includes correspondence related to editions of Party Government, The Semi-Sovereign People, Local Political Surveys, [Political Parties or Party Politics], Two Hundred Million Americans in Search of a Government, page proofs of Local Political Surveys and Two Hundred Million.. ., and cancelled contract for Pressure Groups in Politics (1963).
  - Ho-Iw (Folder 21)
    - Holtzman, Abraham, 1952
    - Horwitz, Robert, 1953
    - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1960
    - Hunt, J. C., 1952
    - Huntington, Samuel P., 1949-1953
    - Hyneman, Charles S., 1953-1954
    - Illinois College, 1953
    - Illinois, State of, 1952 Enc.
    - Independent Citizens’ Committee of the Arts, Sciences and Professions, 1945
    - Institute of Ethics and Politics, 1954 Enc.
    - Institute of Practical Politics, Inc., 1951
    - International City Managers’ Association, 1951
    - Ives, Irving M., 1950
    - Iwanaga, Kenkichiro, 1962-1969
  - J
    - Jack, Douglas S., 1953
    - James Foundation, 1953
    - Johnson, Earl S., 1952 Enc.
    - Johnson, Edwin C., 1968
    - John Price Jones Company, 1950
    - Jones, Victor, 1949-1953, 1962 Enc.
    - Junior Town Meeting League, 1951 Enc.
  - K (Folder 23)
    - Kampelman, Max M., 1950
    - Kansas, University of 1/0, 1950
    - Katz, Melvin, 1954
    - Keena, Thomas E. J., 1953
    - Kefauver, Estes, 1950
    - Kentucky, University of, 1951
    - Kesselman, Louis C., 1949 Enc.
    - Key, V. O., 1947-1955
    - Kiermaier, Jack W., 1957
    - King Features Syndicate, 1951
    - Knopf, Alfred A., Inc., 1944-1953
    - Koblitz, Robert J., 1948-1949
    - Koch, Malcolm, 1953
    - Kohlhase, Norbert, 1952
    - Kotler, Isadore L., 1969
    - Kremm, Walter P., 1952 Enc.
    - Kretzchmar, Heinrich, 1951-1952
  - L-Lo
    - Lancaster, Lane W., 1952
    - Lane, Robert E., 1953
    - Lange, Hermann, 1952-1953
    - Langton, York, 1953
    - Lapham, Lewis J., 1949
    - Laswell, Harold D., 1949
    - Latham, Earl, 1950-1953
    - League of Women Voters of Greater New Haven, 1952
    - League of Women Voters of the City of New York, 1952
    - League of Women Voters of the United States, 1950
    - League of Women Voters of Windsor, Connecticut, 1952
    - Lehbert, Ben, 1950
    - LeMaster, Joseph E., 1948
    - Lewis, John D., 1951
    - Life, 1951
    - Lindbloom, Harold, 1953
    - Lindsey, John W., 1947
    - Little, Eleanor H., 1953
    - Lloyd, David D., 1957
    - Lockard, Duane 1/0, 1954
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1950 Enc.
    - Long Lane School, 1950-1955 Enc.
  - Lo-Ma (Folder 25)
    - Loomis School, 1952
    - Lorish, Robert E., 1953 Enc.
    - Louise, Pierre, 1951
    - Luess, Heinz, 1950-1952
    - Lyford, Joseph P., 1957 Enc.
    - Macalester College, 1953
    - MacCann, Richard Dyer, 1950 Enc.
    - McConaughy, James L. 2/0, 1953
    - McCulloch, Frank W., 1957
    - McKay, Hazel, 1969
    - McKinsey and Company, 1955
    - McMahon, Brien, 1944-1949
    - McManus, Robert H., 1953
    - MacMillan Company, 1954
    - Macomber, William B., 1948
    - Macy, John, 1957
    - Mangone, Gerard J., 1950-1955, 1968 Enc.
  - Ma (Folder 26)
    - Manzullo, Donald A., 1965
    - Martin, Richard, 1951-52
    - Martin, Roscoe C., 1948-1954
    - Maryland, University of, 1947-1953 Enc.
    - Mason, Alpheus Thomas, 1950
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1950, 1965
  - Me-Mi (Folder 27)
    - Mead, Benjamin H., 1953
    - Meeker, Thomas G., 1952-1953
    - Menand, Louis III, 1949, 1951 Enc.
    - Menken, S. Stanwood, 1947-1949 Enc.
    - Mesmer, Gerald J., 1950
    - Michigan, University of, 1948-1952 Enc.
    - Middle States Council for the Social Studies, 1953
    - Middletown, City of, 1951
    - Middletown Democratic Town Committee, 1954
    - Middletown Community Chest, 1951
    - Miller, Howard, 1951
    - Miller, James W., 1953-1954
    - Minneapolis [City of], 1948
    - Minnesota, University of, 1948, 1953
    - Mitchell, Matthew C., 1948-1949 Enc.
      Includes correspondence and documents concerning the founding of the New England Political Science Association.
  - Mo-Na (Folder 28)
    - Moravian College, 1955
    - Mosher, Frederick L., 1951, 1957
    - Mott, Rodney L., 1948, 1952
    - Mount Holyoke College, 1953
    - Mueller, Bernhard, 1951-1953
    - Muirhead, George R., 1953
    - Nadronski, Peter, 1951
    - Naftalin, Arthur, 1953-1954
    - Nati, Arturo, 1952
    - National Association of Manufacturers, 1953
    - National Broadcasting Company, 1957, 1960 Enc.
      Includes copy of contract for "American Government" interview series (1957).
    - National Center for Education in Politics, 1962
    - National Commission on Law Observance and Enforcement, 1931
  - Na-Ne (Folder 29)
    - National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States, 1953-1954
    - National Education Association, 1951
    - National Federation for Constitutional Liberties, 1945 Enc.
    - National Municipal League, 1947-1953
    - Nealon, Rita W., 1952-1953 Enc.
    - Neumann, Franz L., 1948
    - Neumann, Sigmund, 1949-1951
    - Neustadt, Richard, 1957 Enc.
    - New Britain, Connecticut, Public Schools, 1961
    - New Century, 1949-1950 Enc.
    - New Republic, 1950-1954
    - New York Democratic State Committee, 1952
    - New York Herald Tribune, 1951
    - New York Journal-American, 1951
    - New York Times, 1951
    - New York University, 1955
    - New York World Telegram, 1951
    - Newhall, Parker, 1949
  - No-Pf (Folder 30)
    - Northwestern University, 1954
    - Norwich University, 1953
    - Oberlin College, 1951
    - Odegard, Peter H., 1951
    - O’Dwyer, William, 1946
      Includes telegram from Mayor of New York to delegates of the American Political Science Association conference.
    - Ohio State University, 1951
    - Ohio Wesleyan University, 1953
    - Orvis, Kenneth G., 1953
    - Oxford University, 1953
    - Oxford University Press, 1951
    - Owens, John R., 1953
    - Parmelee, Richard C., 1954
    - Parr, F. Van Siclen, 1950
    - Parratt, Spencer D., 1950
    - Peardon, Thomas P., 1953
    - Peek, George A., 1953
    - Pelletier, Lawrence L., 1953, 1960
    - Peltason, Jack, 1949
    - Pennsylvania State College, 1953 Enc.
    - Pennsylvania, University of, 1954 Enc.
    - Pfeifer, Wilhelm, 1951-1953
  - Pi-Q (Folder 31)
    - Pinkerton, Sam-Pearce, 1954 Enc.
    - Planned Parenthood Federation of America, 1961
    - Political Science Quarterly, 1949
    - Polter, Allen, 1948-1954
    - Prentice-Hall Inc., 1936, 1940, 1967
      Includes correspondence concerning Politics, Pressure and the Tariff.
    - Princeton University, 1958
    - Public Administration Clearing House, 1953
    - Public Affairs Information Service, 1951
    - Public Affairs Pamphlets, 1953
    - Purdue University, 1953
    - Purtell, William A., 1954
    - Quayle, Edward, 1968-1970
  - R-Ri (Folder 32)
    - Rackow, Felix, 1953
    - Ranney, Austin, 1947-1954 Enc.
    - Ransom, Harry H., 1953 Enc.
    - Rayburn, Sam, 1950, 1952 Enc.
    - Reed, Solon, 1954
    - Rees, Herb, 1949
    - Reid, Ira De A., 1953-1955
    - Rejai, M., 1967
    - Republic Steel Corporation, 1959
    - Reynolds, Harry W., 1949-1951 Enc.
    - Ribicoff, Abraham A., 1950
    - Ridaut, Frank, 1950-1951
  - Rinehart & Company, 1947-1951 (Folder 33)
    Includes correspondence related to Schattschneider’s work as a consultant editor in Political Science.
  - Ro-Sl (Folder 34)
    - Rockfall Corporation, 1944, 1950
    - Rodriguez, Luis A., 1949
    - Rosenberg, Herbert H., 1950
    - Rosenbloom, Marc, 1945
    - Rowe, Peterson & Co., 1960
    - Rubinow, Raymond S., 1953
    - Rustow, Dankwart A., 1951
    - Sanphy, Elizabeth A., 1964
    - Sarah Lawrence College, 1950-1954
    - Saybrook Rotary Club, 1951
    - Schriftgiesser, Karl, 1948
    - Schuck, Victoria, 1953-1954
    - Schwebel, Devora D., 1953
    - Scott, Andrew, 1954
    - Scott, Foresman and Company, 1953
    - See, Edgar T., 1968
    - Sharkansky, Ira, 1968
    - Simmons, Ernest J., 1967
    - Sirotkin, Phillip, 1953
    - Sivak, Paul D., 1950
    - Skelley, Joseph F., undated
    - Slate, W. L., 1951
  - William Sloane Associates, Inc., 1948-1952 (Folder 35)
    Includes correspondence relating to Schattschneider’s position as consulting editor and to A Guide to the Study of Public Affairs (1950-1951).
  - Sm-Sy (Folder 36)
    - Smith, Christopher A., circa 1950s
    - Smith College, 1955
    - Smith, Harry, Jr., 1953
    - Smith, Howard R., 1951
    - Smith, Richard P., 1953
    - Snow, Wilbert, 1951
    - Social Science Research Council, 1944-1945
    - Soloman, Samuel R., 1951
    - Somers, H. M., 1952
    - Southbury Training School, 1952 Enc.
    - Sprague, David G., 1953
    - Stamps, Norman L., 1949
    - Stark, Roger, 1954
    - Stedman, Murray S., Jr., 1948-1949
    - Steiger, Mathias, 1950-1951
    - Steinel, Agnes T., 1945
    - Stevenson, Adlai E., 1952
    - Stewart, Robert B., 1954 Enc.
    - Stivly, John O., circa 1950s
    - Straetz, Ralph A., 1948
    - Stringfellow, William, 1953
    - Sutherland, Arthur E., 1951
    - Swanson, Thor, 1951
    - Swarthmore College, 1950-1951
    - Syracuse University, 1950-53
  - T-Un (Folder 37)
    - Tang, Peter Sheng-Hao, 1953-1954 Enc.